the market is under-estimating the scale
of transaction activity that will take
place 10 years from now. It could
multiply 10x, 100x, or more as we move
into a world of agentic [music] finance.
I think it's orders of magnitude bigger.
>> For investors trying to position
themselves in this very convoluted
world, should they be looking at the
tokenized assets [music]
or the underlying rails that make the
whole thing possible?
>> That's a great question. If you as an
investor want to benefit from
tokenization, you have to own the
infrastructure that makes it happen.
That means owning high-performance layer
ones like Ethereum and Solana [music]
that serve as the basis for
tokenization. It means owning Oracle
providers like Chainlink that help
connect [music]
blockchains to the real world.
>> Now, we are seeing obviously the biggest
names really take on this technology
full steam ahead. Is this institutional
involvement validating the technology or
does it risk [music] steering
tokenization in a direction that looks a
lot like the current financial system?
>> Oh, great question. Both is the answer
to that. You are seeing, however, parts
of Wall Street trying to do effectively
regulatory capture on how this spills
out into the world. Ultimately, I think
the technology will win, but for sure
banks are trying to capture some of that
value themselves in a way that doesn't
help end investors.
>> One of your more recent [music] clips
that went pretty viral was your Mount
Rushmore. But one in that four [music]
that definitely stands out as unique, of
course, is Chainlink. Spot Chainlink
[music] ETFs went live December 2025
with Bitwise's going live in early
January. [music]
Since then, we haven't seen a single
week of net outflows. What do you think
that signals?
>> I think it signals that investors get
it. It's such a critical piece of the
infrastructure. Right way to think about
a blockchain like Ethereum's or Solana
is it's like a really powerful Excel
spreadsheet on a computer that's not
connected to the internet. But if it
wants to know the price of a stock or
the price of a bond or the value of a
currency, it needs a bridge or a link to
get that data. So, if your thesis is
more real-world assets are going to come
on chain, they effectively all have to
flow through and interact with
Chainlink.
>> I do want to play devil's [music]
advocate. When new technologies emerge,
they tend to increase efficiency, but
also concentrate power among the biggest
players. What makes [music] tokenization
potentially different, and should we
expect the same outcome?
>> It's a great question. I think the thing
you should hope for is not that it gets
to perfect, but that it gets to better.
But, you're right to point out that
there will be downsides. There will be
new risks that emerge as well. I think
that that is just true.
>> Hey guys, just real quick before we dive
into this amazing interview with Matt.
If you haven't noticed, we have one
subscriber on this channel. Now, if
you're not aware who I am, my name is
Ryan McTollo. I used to run the Crypto
[music] Fiend YouTube channel in 2017
all the way up to 2022, where we had
over 100,000 members. [music]
Since then, I've had the amazing
opportunity to make content alongside
people like Nicholas Merten [music] over
on Data Dash, as well as do production
for people like Gary Cardone, as well as
Scott Melker [music] over at the Wolf of
All Streets. Now, we're going full
circle, and we are back on our own
channel. So, if you love journalistic
deep dives and great interviews, this
might just be the channel for you. Now,
I'm not going to ask you to subscribe
right now because I feel like that's
something that needs to be earned. So,
throughout the duration of this video,
at any point [music] when you see the
subscribe button pop up, if you feel
like I've earned your subscription at
that point, go ahead and hit the
subscribe button so you don't miss out
on great interviews and deep dives like
this one. All right, thank you for
joining Matt.
So, when people hear tokenization, it
can kind of sound like a buzzword, you
know, but at a fundamental level, what
is the real problem in global capital
markets that tokenization actually
solves? And do you actually believe we
will reach a world where the most most
of the financial institutions and assets
live on chain?
>> Yeah, all assets are going on chain. So,
I'll answer the second part of that
question first cuz it's very easy.
Uh you don't have to listen to me. The
The chairman of the SEC says all assets
are going on chain. The CEO of
BlackRock, the world's largest asset
manager, says all assets are going on
chain. And so, when I say all assets are
going on chain, I'm in good company.
To go to the former question, the
problem that tokenization solves is that
our current financial infrastructure is
built like from the 1920s. Uh stocks
settle T+1.
Uh behind the scenes, the the the system
that allows stocks to settle is this
complex Rube Goldberg-style contraption
with a half dozen different names and
money shuttling here and there.
Um stock markets trade, you know,
6 and 1/2 hours a day, 5 days a week.
That's just not the world that we live
in. The world we live in is global. It's
instant. It's 24/7 365.
And it's not possible for the existing
ecosystem to speed up to that. Uh
sort of moving that forward would be
years and years and years of work.
Tokenization allows all that to happen
instantly. It allows assets to move 24/7
365 on a global basis with instantaneous
settlement. It is the email to the the
traditional snail mail for securities
movement, and I think it's fait accompli
that it's how all assets will move in
the future.
>> You've clearly been uh probably the
biggest advocate for tokenization.
Um especially as of recent. So, if
tokenization does really grow into a
multi-trillion dollar market, one thing
that one thing that I think um you would
agree with that is insanely overlooked
is that a lot of the opportunity
opportunity may not actually sit in the
assets being brought on chain
themselves, but in the infrastructure
that connects blockchains to real-world
tradfi systems. So, for investors trying
to position themselves in this very
convoluted world of uh blockchain and
tokenization, should they be looking at
the tokenized assets or the underlying
rails that make the whole thing
possible?
>> Well, that's a great question. There are
marginal benefits to you to owning a
tokenized asset. You can trade it 24/7.
It's easier to get a loan against it.
It's more useful. But, if you tokenize
an ETF or you tokenize Tesla shares, at
the end of the day, it's an ETF or it's
Tesla shares. That's the bulk of your
return. Yes, it's a little more
functional. Yes, it's a little more
flexible. But, really there's not a big
difference. If you as an investor want
to benefit from tokenization, you have
to loan own the infrastructure that
makes it happen. That means owning
high-performance layer ones like
Ethereum and Solana that serve as the
basis for tokenization. It means owning
oracle providers like Chainlink that
help connect sort of blockchains to the
real world and provide real-world
information back to those blockchains
about tokenized assets. And it means
owning the companies that are building
aggressively in the space. This is a
once-in-a-generation
or once-in-every-three-generation
upgrade in the world's financial
ecosystem.
Every time that happens, there's massive
opportunities. And And as an investor,
you want to position yourself to benefit
from that.
>> One of your uh more recent clips that
went pretty viral was your Mount
Rushmore. I thought it was great. It
really hit the nail on the head for I
think what um
a lot of people are trying to figure out
what's relevant, what's not.
Maybe there's more relevancy than just
the four that you picked.
But one in that four that definitely
stands out as unique, of course, is
Chainlink.
And one thing that I've seen recently
that is pretty fascinating,
you know, spot Chainlink ETFs went live
in December 2025 with Bitwise is going
live in early January. Since then, we
haven't seen a single week of net
outflows even with the poor sentiment
that we've been having the last few
months. What do you think that signals?
>> Yeah, I think it signals that investors
get it. It's such a critical piece of
the infrastructure. Right, the right
right way to think about a blockchain
like Ethereum's or Solana is it's like a
really powerful Excel spreadsheet on a
computer that's not connected to the
internet. It can do amazing math,
amazing calculations. But if it wants to
know the price of a stock or the price
of a bond or the value of a currency or
the outcome of an event or what day it
is or anything else about the outside
world, it needs a bridge or a link to
get that data. Chainlink has by far the
dominant market share in that market.
It's something like 70 to 80% market
share providing that link between these
blockchains and the real world. So if
your thesis is more real-world assets
are going to come on chain, they
effectively all have to flow through and
interact with Chainlink is it's such a
powerful story and people are making the
bet that this is a fundamental piece of
how global markets will work for the
next 30, 40, 50 years and it's trading
at a valuation of like six or seven
billion dollars. I mean, it's really
relatively small. So I think that's very
attractive and I think that's why you've
seen the consistent, steady, small, but
building inflows into those products.
>> Now, another clip of yours that went
pretty viral was um
you recently mentioned that one of your
buddies over at BlackRock announced that
um they want to bring all of their ETFs
live within 12 months, I believe.
If tokenization works the way we believe
it will, what does the financial system
look like not even 12 months, but 10
years from now? What changes for
everyday investors? And what would make
them realize something fundamental has
shifted in their everyday lives?
>> Yeah, first I have to warn you that
there's no off button. In the TradFi
world, it's kind of nice that markets
shut down at 4:00 on Friday and you can
have your weekends off and then come
back at 9:30 on Monday and start again.
One thing will shift is that that's not
true, right? Markets will trade 24/7,
365, and you'll have to have systems to
deal with it. Now, I think that's a net
good for the world. If there's a big
geopolitical event, you can reposition
your portfolio accordingly instead of
waiting for the markets to open, but
that will be one big change. The other
big change is that all of your
traditional assets will be able to
access the things that are available in
DeFi today from a crypto perspective.
So, something that I think will happen
is people will start taking more loans
against their existing assets or using
those as an asset or resource. You can
do that in TradFi if you're wealthy. If
you have $100,000 or a million dollars
at Schwab, you can take loans against
your stocks in certain circumstances,
but DeFi makes that very easy. So, once
we're in a tokenized world, I think the
kind of services that the wealthiest
investors to get today in traditional
brokerages will be available to every
investor through DeFi protocols, and I
think that will be pretty exciting as
well.
>> Yeah, you you really um flowed into my
next question here, which is
some of the most powerful ideas behind
tokenization is that
this could open markets globally
allowing somewhere
anywhere in the world to own a
fractional piece of assets, real estate,
bonds,
even private credit in the United
States. That is massive and I think
definitely overlooked. But do you think
tokenization could become the biggest
financial inclusion tool we've ever seen
and are there any any negative
trade-offs to that?
>> Yeah, so so the first answer is yes,
absolutely, right? It puts that access
to all the world's most interesting
investments in the hands eventually of
everyone around the globe who has a cell
phone, which is a remarkable thing and
it should let them self-custody those
tokens. It's just tremendously opening
up and I know many of us who are
fortunate don't have to worry about that
kind of access, but most people around
the world don't have it. So I think that
that is a very real thing. Are there
downside risks to that? Of course. So
one downside risk, which we see in
crypto, is that people are still human.
So on nights and weekends the market is
less liquid than it is during the day
cuz people are asleep. And when you have
shock events, you can get big amounts of
of of of sell-offs, right? Because
you're in a low liquidity environment.
You'll also be able to see more leverage
build up in the system, which can be
valuable for people, but also introduces
risks. We see that in crypto in events
like 10/10. So it's not like it's
wonderful in every possible way. It's
both inevitable and better for most
people, but some of the negative things
we see in crypto around low liquidity
events and and leverage blowouts, I
think we'll start to happen in the
traditional market as well. So that's
something people will have to watch out
for.
Now, we are seeing obviously the biggest
names really take on this technology
full steam ahead, BlackRock, JP Morgan,
many major exchanges. From your
perspective, is this institutional
involvement validating the technology or
does it risk steering tokenization in a
direction that looks a lot like the
current financial system?
>> Oh, great question. Both is the answer
to that. So, it is enormously
validating. Those of us in crypto have
been arguing that 9:30 to 4:00 p.m.
stock trading and T+1 or just a few
years ago T+2 settlement is absurd in an
age where you can get anything delivered
by Amazon in a second, right? So, it
seems ridiculous. And Wall Street is
recognizing this. They recognize that
they have to build on this space.
You are seeing, however, parts of Wall
Street trying to do effectively
regulatory capture on how this spills
out into the world. It can only happen
on quasi-private chains. It can only
happen within a small ecosystem.
Uh DeFi uh innovators shouldn't have
protection from legal lawsuits, right?
You see all of that forces in the
lobbying to sort of distort what the
Clarity Act is, etc. So, we need to be
on our guard that uh the ecosystem that
we get is one that is open, that is
permissionless with reasonable
constraints on things like AML, KYC, and
that is truly advantageous to the
people, that lowers costs, that improves
uptime, etc. Because there is an attempt
in any time there's a disruption for
regulatory capture. I certainly see that
in the market. So, it's something we
should be
watching closely. Ultimately, I think
the technology will win, but for sure
banks are trying to capture some of that
value themselves in a way that doesn't
help end investors.
>> Now, one of the things I love about a
lot of the voices in um the crypto and
blockchain world is they're They're
afraid to necessarily call balls and
strikes when they see fit. But financial
history does show that when new
technologies emerge, whether it's
electronic trading or ETFs, they tend to
increase efficiency, but also
concentrate power among the biggest
players. What makes tokenization
potentially different, and should we
expect the same outcome?
>> It's a great question.
Um should we expect the largest players
in the space to have large market share?
I think the answer to that is that is
probably the most likely outcome. So,
what do I mean by that? Do I think like
Ethereum, Solana, and a few other chains
will be the primary layer ones? I
absolutely do.
Um do I think large asset managers will
try to still hold a chokehold on
creating assets? I absolutely do. I
think the thing you should hope for is
not that it gets to perfect, but that it
gets to better. So, if you take the
example of ETFs, it's definitely true it
created a number of large giants in the
space. It introduced some distortions
into the market with the rise of passive
taking up such a place in the market,
but it also dramatically shrunk fees,
right? From a percent to 10 basis
points, and therefore puts hundreds of
billions of dollars in everyone's
pockets every year. That's a trade-off
that I'll make. If you think about
brokerage accounts moving from fixed
commissions that were $200 a share to
today's zero with Robinhood, there are
negatives to that, too. There's payment
for order flow, there's all sorts of
things in the market, but broadly
speaking, that was a net improvement.
So, we've always been perfecting this
financial ecosystem, and I agree that
the growth of tokenization could create
some imperfect outcomes. But broadly
speaking, I think it will dramatically
draw down costs, dramatically increase
financial inclusion, and so should we
should fight for the benefits, try to
limit the negatives.
Um but you're right to point out that
there will be downsides. There will be
new risks that emerge as well. I think
that that is just true.
>> Now, like I said earlier, you
uh
outside of you just being with Bitwise,
you seem to always have your pulse on
the up-and-coming. Is there anything on
your radar that you see in the
foreseeable future, maybe the next year,
2 years, outside of tokenization that
has your attention right now?
>> Yeah, well, I think, you know, for for
one, there's a what's old is new again.
I think people dramatically
underestimate the size, scale, and
actually economic opportunity in DeFi.
Um I think DeFi had such a boom and a
bust that people have effectively
written it off. I think many of the DeFi
protocols like Aave and Uniswap, etc.,
have the potential to be a 100x larger
than they are today, really critical
pieces of financial infrastructure. And
then, of course, I'm not the only one
talking about this, but the rise of
agentic finance I think is going to
reshape things dramatically. The one
thing I'm sure of in that is that the
market is underestimating the scale of
transaction activity that will take
place 10 years from now. It's not like
the existing market for TradFi assets
will be the same size as the market for
tokenized assets. Both the number of
assets that will be on chain or
available will grow dramatically. And
then the transaction activity I think
could multiply 10x, 100x, or more as we
move into a world of agentic finance. Um
so, I think people are they acknowledge
that agentic finance is a thing, but I
don't think they're thinking about what
it means from a scale perspective. I
think it's it's orders of magnitude
bigger. So, that's something I'm
thinking about a lot.
>> Yeah, I know uh Brian Armstrong just
came out pretty publicly online about
it, and uh he always seems to be ahead
of the curve, so
Matt, thank you so much for your time. I
really appreciate it.